Brian Daza

Research Assistant, Universidad del Pacífico Research Center (Lima, Peru) dazavbn@gmail.com (+51 1) 958551920 sites.google.com/view/briandaza linkedin.com/in/dazavbn/

Bachelor in Economics interested in following a research career in the field of development. My main interests are poverty, labor economics and education. Incoming student in the Master's Program in Data, Economics, and Development Policy at the Massachusetts Institute of Technology in 2020.

EDUCATION

Degrees

B.Sc., Economics. Universidad Nacional Mayor de San Marcos

2016

Extension Programs

Micromaster in Data, Economics and Development Policy. Massachusetts Institute of Technology on edX 2018

X Advanced Finance University Extension Course. Central Reserve Bank of Peru

XVII SBS Extension Program. Superintendence of Banks, Insurance and PFAs

LXII Advanced Economics University Extension Course. Central Reserve Bank of Peru

2016

ACADEMIC EXPERIENCE

Research Experience

Research Center of Universidad del Pacífico

April 2018 – Current

Research Assistant of Jorge Dávalos

Support on statistical modelling and analysis related with topics on labor, infraestructure and agriculture.

Teaching Experience

Universidad Nacional Mayor de San Marcos

Teaching Assistant:

Introduction to Macroeconomics
 Introduction to Macroeconomics
 Introduction to Microeconomics
 2014
 Introduction to Microeconomics

ORGANIZATIONS

Behavioral Economics and Data Science Team

June 2017 - Current

Multidisciplinary team focused on the dissemination, research and application of behavioral economics, data science and related areas.

- Responsible for impact evaluation classes in Applied Behavioral Economics Courses
- Responsible for the elaboration of the methodology of intervention and evaluation of "Proyecto Best Educa"
- Blog articles (in Spanish):
 - Between empiricism and science: A responsible use of the power of data
 - Towards a political behavioral economics?

PUBLIC SECTOR EXPERIENCE

Ministry of Education

May 2017 – December 2017

Unit of Planning and Budget

Consultant – Economic Assistant

 Data processing and budget analysis of the gaps in teaching and administrative positions at the national level, with the objective of optimizing the use of budgetary resources and strengthening educational management. Ministry of Transport and Communications

September 2016 – December 2016

General Directorate for Telecommunication Control and Supervision Consultant – Economic Assistant

- Data analysis and construction of indicators relevant to communications sector. Improved data recording, facilitating the execution of processes and the development of statistics.
- Improved the prioritization criteria used by the Directorate-General based in research related to the theory of enforcement of law.

SEMINARS AND MEETINGS

Presenter

 $2019 \ 6^{th}$ Congress of the Peruvian Economic Association.

Lima, Peru.

2018 VI National Seminar on Education Research of the Peruvian Society of Educational Research. Cusco, Peru

 4^{th} Economics Workshop $\Omega B\Gamma$. Universidad Nacional Mayor de San Marcos. Lima, Peru. 2015 First Meeting of Young Researchers in Economics. Universidad Nacional Mayor de San Marcos. Lima, Peru.

Attendant

2015 IMF-World Bank Annual Meetings.

Lima, Peru

RESEARCH IN PROGRESS

Effect of the increase of the educational supply on schooling and adolescent work in rural Peru

About 40% of the current educational supply of secondary level in the Peruvian rural area has been established in the last ten years. This research uses the increase of educational supply with the objective of identifying the effects of educational services on schooling and adolescent labor participation in rural areas. A generalized difference in differences method is used, relying on information from the National Household Survey and the Register of Educational Institutions of the Ministry of Education. Among the findings, I found that the increase in educational services in the rural area has had an impact on school enrollment, in the years of education attained and on the prevalence of teenage labor. However, heterogeneous effects are discussed related to differences in the intensity of rurality and the gender of adolescents.

This project was a winner of the First Scholarship Contest for Young Researchers organized by the Peruvian Education Research Society, under the title in Spanish: "Efecto del aumento de la oferta educativa en la escolaridad y el trabajo adolescente en el Perú rural".

The impact of B corporations on the economic and social inclusion of women in Latin America, a pseudo-experimental approach

With J. Dávalos, M.A. Prialé, and E. F. Ninahuanca

This study estimates the causal impact of female entrepreneurship on purpose-driven companies (i.e. exhibit responsible entrepreneurship) and of purpose-driven companies on female employment. We empirical analyse a Latin American sample of companies that participated in the B Impact Assessment questionnaire. Given the significant imbalance in this longitudinal database, we adopt a pseudo-experimental methodology (instrumental variables) with a dimension reduction and imputation algorithm technique. Our results suggest that, while female entrepreneurship has a positive influence on responsible entrepreneurship, there is no significant effect of responsible entrepreneurship on female employment.

SKILLS

Languages: Spanish, native. English, fluent (TOEFL iBT: 110/120)

Software: Stata, R, Python, MATLAB, Excel, LATEX

ACHIEVEMENTS

- Beca Presidente 2019.
- Winner of the First Scholarship Contest for Young Researchers (2018) organized by the Peruvian Education Research Society (SIEP) with the support of UNICEF.
- Second place in the National High School Mathematics Olympiad 2007. Level I Alpha Category.
- Graduated in first place Secondary Education. School Pedro Ruiz Gallo Bongará, Amazonas.
- Chosen by the students as undergraduate student representative in the Faculty Council in the period 2013-2014.

COURSES

- "Introduction to Data Science in Python". Course offered by University of Michigan on Coursera
- "Theoretical and Empirical Approaches: Natural Resources Blessing or Curse". Course offered by CISEPA, the Research Center of Sociology, Economics, Politics and Anthropology of the Pontificia Universidad Católica del Perú
- "Designing and Running Randomized Evaluations". Course offered by the *Data, Economics, and Development Policy* MicroMasters program, an online learning initiative offered by the Massachusetts Institute of Technology in collaboration with edX.
- "The Challenges of Global Poverty". Course offered by the *Data, Economics, and Development Policy* MicroMasters program, an online learning initiative offered by the Massachusetts Institute of Technology in collaboration with edX.
- "Data Analysis for Social Scientists". Course offered by the *Data*, *Economics*, and *Development Policy* MicroMasters program, an online learning initiative offered by the Massachusetts Institute of Technology in collaboration with edX.
- "Foundations of Development Policy: Advanced Development Economics". Course offered by the *Data, Economics, and Development Policy* MicroMasters program, an online learning initiative offered by the Massachusetts Institute of Technology in collaboration with edX.
- "Risk Management in Insurance Companies". Course offered by Toronto Centre. March 28 to April 01, 2016.
- Simulator "Strategic Management of Risks in Financial Institutions". Course conducted by Sparkassenstiftung für internationale Kooperation. March 14 to 18, 2016.

Updated on July 4, 2019